<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian Schuth</title>
    <link>http://bschuth.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brian Schuth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 11:33:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bschuth.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merton and Zhuangzi</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/merton-zhuangzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 11:33:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/merton-zhuangzi/</guid>
      <description>For some time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the journals of Thomas Merton, for reasons I may discuss at some later date. I&amp;rsquo;m in the fourth volume of seven, in the early 1960s.
After mentioning the Zhuangzi book in my chain of reading post, it occurred to me that Merton&amp;rsquo;s interest in Chinese philosophy is an important development in this volume of the journals, so I went to the index to find where Zhuangzi is mentioned (as Chuang Tzu in the old romanization).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s Chain of Reading</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/todays-chain-of-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 09:38:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/todays-chain-of-reading/</guid>
      <description>I am in danger of not getting anything done because of reading things online today, and many of those things I am reading online are making me want to read other things&amp;hellip;
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I got here. I was on Hacker News and went to a blog entry entitled &amp;ldquo;Time Spent Programming Is Often Time Well Spent&amp;rdquo; by Eugene Wallingford, a computer science professor in Iowa. Next to that was the post I [mention in my book list]({{ref /plans/books-to-read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 September 2020</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/homework/23-september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 20:21:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/homework/23-september-2020/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of my &amp;ldquo;fall semester&amp;rdquo;, I here place my homework. Don&amp;rsquo;t suppose it is of public interest, but it can&amp;rsquo;t hurt to put it out there.
Greek  I reset the 900+ items in my Hansen and Quinn list in Studies, and took on 100 of them tonight. Only did one of the Chapter 10 exercises, #4. Will have to attend to more of them tomorrow.  C++ Did exercise 51 from Chapter 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books to Read</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/plans/books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:53:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/plans/books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>Oh, my god. This is my biggest problem, the huge list of books that look interesting to me that I want to read.
New Books Titles I&amp;rsquo;ve come across that make me want to read them:
 The Battle of the Classics, Eric Adler, OUP. Saw this in an email from Oxford; as a programmer with a philosophy degree, the father of two English majors, a music major, and the husband of a violin performance major, and a guy who is trying to read ancient Greek in his spare time, justification of education in the humanities is something I care a lot about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Classes</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/plans/future-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:37:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/plans/future-classes/</guid>
      <description>If I were to create more &amp;ldquo;classes&amp;rdquo; of my own devising, here&amp;rsquo;s my list of what I want to address:
 Learning Clojure (with SICP as a secondary text) Greek Tragedy (focus on reading Greek, but with practical additions. One tragedy at a time.) Software Architecture Lit Review (how to consolidate all those books and all that I&amp;rsquo;ve read over all this time?) German for Bach Cantatas (supports the yearly listening, simple way to absorb a sub-vocabulary of German) Building a Simple Compiler/Interpreter (because of the Crafting Interpreters book I heard about, and mentioned here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2020 Semester</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/fall2020-semester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 11:29:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/fall2020-semester/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in college for decades, but I always feel as though I should be returning to school in September. Looking at where I am at this point in my life, what courses should I be taking?
For work, I am about to make a transition to C++, and I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with questions about the design of the platform I have to live in. In my personal life, I&amp;rsquo;ve used this unusual year to get myself into better running and biking shape than I have been in before, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rabbit Hole with Dance</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/a-sudden-hunger-for-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 09:30:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/a-sudden-hunger-for-dance/</guid>
      <description>Last week I suddenly watched a lot of dance, via a roundabout inspiration. My brother asked me for some suggestions about pieces by Philip Glass that might interest his son.
That got me thinking about Glass again, which got me thinking about Steve Reich, and thinking about Reich reminded me of the piece that the Dutch choreographer Anna Teresa de Keersmaeker created using Reich&amp;rsquo;s Violin Phase.. That also got me thinking about Lucinda Child&amp;rsquo;s choreography for Glass&#39; Einstein on the Beach, which totally hypnotized me when I saw that work at BAM back in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:06:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bschuth.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I expect to place short notes here, something of a public journal. I&amp;rsquo;m writing from Eastport, where the weather took a turn from the feverish to the sharply crisp on Thursday night. As I was struggling to sleep, the north wind suddenly rose up, sounding at first like a locomotive, or the shock wave from an explosion. When it became clear there was no fireball behind the breeze, but instead only colder air, I was able to drift off after wrapping myself more closely in my comforter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
